<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<databaseChangeLog
    xmlns="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog
      http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-4.1.xsd">

    <changeSet author="nathan.russell@valtech.com" id="0001_EIP1-3454_update_certificate - populate issuing_authority_cy column">
        <sql>
            <comment>
                Set issuing_authority_cy to the best value we can for existing Welsh language certificates.
                Setting this field for existing certificates will prevent null pointer exceptions if these certificates are ever reprinted.
                The 'best value' we can set is `Swyddog Cofrestru Etholiadol` which translates as `Electoral Registration Officer` rather than the actual Welsh Issuing Authority.
                This is deemed acceptable as that is the value that would have been printed (incorrectly) on the original certificate when printed for the first time.
                Over and above that we do not have the Welsh Local Authority name in the context of the execution of this running liquibase migration - the actual value is only
                available at runtime when we call the ERO Management REST API to get the relevant ERO and local authorities.

                This is not guaranteed to fix all Welsh certificates unfortunately. There are some certificates in the production database that are meant to be Welsh/Dual Language
                but have their `certificate_language` field set to `EN`. This is because they were created before bugfix EIP1-3314 was deployed and their `certificate_language` field
                was incorrectly set based on the language the applicant used when creating their initial application on the IER site. We have no way of easily identifying those records.
                (We could possibly identify them via their gssCode starting with `W` but we won't have the rest of the Welsh LA data such as address etc to correct all of the data)
            </comment>
            UPDATE certificate c
            INNER JOIN print_request pr on c.id = pr.certificate_id
            SET c.issuing_authority_cy = 'Swyddog Cofrestru Etholiadol'
            WHERE pr.certificate_language = 'CY'
        </sql>

        <rollback/>
    </changeSet>

</databaseChangeLog>
